Truth. Justice. Whatever.
Supergirl is a action, adventure, science fiction
film directed by Craig Gillespie.
While celebrating her 21st birthday, Kara Zor-El travels across the galaxy with her dog Krypto, during
which she meets the young Ruthye Marye Knoll and goes on a "murderous quest for revenge".
Kara Zor-El / Supergirl, played by Milly Alcock.
Krem of the Yellow Hills, played by Matthias Schoenaerts.
Ruthye Mary Knoll, played by Eve Ridley.
Lobo, played by Jason Momoa.
Zor-El, played by David Krumholtz.
Alura In-Ze, played by Emily Beecham.
Supergirl is an upcoming American superhero film based on
the eponymous character from DC Comics.
Directed by Craig Gillespie and written by Ana Nogueira, it
will be the second film in the DC Universe (DCU).
Milly Alcock stars as Kara Zor-El / Supergirl, alongside Matthias Schoenaerts,
Eve Ridley, David Krumholtz, Emily Beecham, and Jason Momoa.
In the film, Supergirl travels across the galaxy
on a murderous quest for revenge.
It is produced by James Gunn and Peter Safran of DC Studios.
A film featuring Supergirl entered development as part of the DC Extended Universe (DCEU) franchise in August
2018, and the character was introduced in the 2023 film The Flash, portrayed by Sasha Calle.
Plans for the standalone project were altered when Gunn and
Safran became co-CEOs of DC Studios in October 2022.
A new Supergirl film was announced in January 2023 as an adaptation of the 2021–22 comic
book miniseries Supergirl: Woman of Tomorrow by Tom King and Bilquis Evely.
Nogueira was hired by November 2023; Alcock was cast in January 2024 to debut in
the first DCU film, Superman (2025); and Gillespie joined that May.
Filming took place from January to May 2025 at Warner Bros.
Studios Leavesden and London in England, and in Scotland.
Supergirl is scheduled to be released by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United States on June 26, 2026.
It will be part of the DCU's Chapter One: Gods and Monsters.
The film explores themes of hero, superhero, villain,
based on comic, female protagonist.
The tone is thought_provoking.